FERNANDO RODRIGO ANSILIERO



PROFILE

Professional over 13 years of IT experience. My last position was at BRF company Brazil, as a SAM Analyst providing compliance and reduction of large Software contracts, such as Microsoft. I am certified in Scrum PSMI and have experience in Project Management of medium complexity. I also participated as a PMO of the HSBC Basel project. I have interest in Software Licensing, IT Projects, Governance and IT Processes, IT service desk.

CONTACT

- P: +44 7576612868
- E: fernando.ansiliero@gmail.com
- L: linkedin.com/in/fransiliero

EXPERIENCE

BRF

(+ 110k employees)

2015 - Feb/2019

Sam Analyst

- · Responsible for BRF Software Asset Management team.
- Directly responsible of Microsoft, SAP, Oracle, Autodesk and Tableau license Management, agreements and full lifecycle.
- · Compliance & software reconciliation on Snow SLM and Optimizer (SAP).
- · In charge of IT CAPEX control and consolidation (>30M U\$).
- · Strong skilled in Snow Software SLM and Snow Optimizer for SAP.
- Experience in purchasing software and agreements (ARIBA-SAP)
- · Experience in models and types of Microsoft licensing.
- Management of up to 15000 devices including servers and desktops (large scale).
- Implementation of ITAM Project and KPI to measure effectiveness (Snow, ITSM, ISO 19770 practices).
- 10M U\$ of reduction in Microsoft and Oracle agreements.

HSBC - Stefanini

2014 - 2015

Project Analyst

Basileia II Project

- · Responsible for organization and chronogram
- · Knowledge in CA Clarity and Open Workbench.
- · Weekly status report for stakeholders, team and developers.
- · Monthly status report for executive team in steering commit.
- · Discussion and negotiation of deadline.
- · Risk analysis and communication.

America Latina Logistica

2013 - 2014

Infrastructure Analyst

- · Change Management, Call Management
- Coordination of the Tezza Project (new company) for hardware equipment and user migration.
- Homologation of systems aimed at specific sectors of the business in a new environment (Sygno RH, XRT, Risk Control)
- · Asset Management and Hardware Inventory control.
- Responsible for the management and maintenance of e-mail accounts in the O365 portal.

EXPERIENCE

Premier IT – Volvo/GVT/Metso

2007 - 2012

IT Analyst | Premier IT

- · Hardware management and equipment life cycle.
- · Third-party internal team leadership.
- · Attendance of calls and creation of procedures for IT staff.
- · Maintenance in notebooks and printers.
- Management of partners for field service.

EDUCATION

Post-Graduation | UNISUL University

IT Project Management

Mar 2011 - Sep 2012

Graduation | UNISUL University

Information Technology Management

Jun 2007 - Dec 2009

EXPERTISE

Leadership & ability to work on a

team

Written and Verbal

Communication

Organizational Skills

Multi-tasking

Time Management

Able to Operate Under Pressure

LANGUAGES

PORTUGUESE



ENGLISH

